<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="154" moduleid="6296" modulename="book" contextid="24976">
  <book id="154">
    <name>Introducing Workforce Preparation Activities</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;Insert Description here.&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1495462467</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1511984165</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1092">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Adult education and literacy activities:  WIOA adult education and literacy activities defined</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Under WIOA, Adult Education and Literacy Activities refer to “programs, activities, and services that include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*6319@$&amp;amp;mode=entry&amp;amp;hook=309" target="_blank"&gt;adult education&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*6319@$&amp;amp;mode=letter&amp;amp;hook=L&amp;amp;sortkey=&amp;amp;sortorder=asc" target="_blank"&gt;literacy&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*6319@$&amp;amp;mode=entry&amp;amp;hook=323" target="_blank"&gt;work­place adult education and literacy activities&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*6319@$&amp;amp;mode=letter&amp;amp;hook=F&amp;amp;sortkey=&amp;amp;sortorder=asc" target="_blank"&gt;family literacy activities&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*6319@$&amp;amp;mode=entry&amp;amp;hook=324" target="_blank"&gt;English language acquisition activities&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*6319@$&amp;amp;mode=letter&amp;amp;hook=I&amp;amp;sortkey=&amp;amp;sortorder=asc" target="_blank"&gt;integrated English literacy and civics education&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*6319@$&amp;amp;mode=entry&amp;amp;hook=322" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;workforce preparation activities&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;; or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*6319@$&amp;amp;mode=letter&amp;amp;hook=I&amp;amp;sortkey=&amp;amp;sortorder=asc" target="_blank"&gt;integrated education and training.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;img width="550" height="366" alt="Two adult English language learners reading" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/64949476_m%20%281%29.jpg" style="vertical-align: text-bottom;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WIOA describes workforce preparation activities as activities, programs, and services to help an individual acquire a combination of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basic academic skills;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*6319@$&amp;amp;mode=entry&amp;amp;hook=305" target="_blank"&gt;critical thinking skills&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*6319@$&amp;amp;mode=entry&amp;amp;hook=311" target="_blank"&gt;digital literacy&lt;/a&gt; skills; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;self-management skills; as well as&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;competencies in
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;utilizing resources;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using information;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;working with others;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;understanding systems; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;obtaining skills necessary for successful transition into and completion of postsecondary education or training, or employment (WIOA. 2014. Sec 203).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These skills will be examined in more detail later in this session. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Calibri;" face="Calibri"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1501088922</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1093">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Workforce preparation aligns with employability skills framework </title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Workforce preparation activities align closely with the&lt;span class="nolink"&gt; Employability Skills Framework, a re&lt;/span&gt;source that provides information and tools to inform the instruction and assessment of employability skills. The Framework, which you will explore more closely later in this course, was developed as part of the Support for States Employability Standards in Career and Technical Education (CTE) and Adult Education Project, an initiative of the U.S. Department of Education’s Office of Career, Technical, and Adult Education (OCTAE).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Employability%20Skills%20Framework%20Screenshot_7-11.JPG" width="550" height="524" alt="Screenshot of the Employability Skills Framework" style="float: left;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1501083646</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1094">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Labor market trends and input from employers inform workforce preparation and employability skills</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Employability skills and workforce preparation activities are informed by research on labor market trends and reflect input from business and industry leaders and employers about the skills they need, seek, and value in their employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employers in the 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; century knowledge-driven economy require their employees to have different skills than they did in an economy driven primarily by industrial production. In the knowledge economy, employers seek a workforce with skills that are general and transferable, such as the ability to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reason;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;communicate; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solve problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/21cstCenturySkills.jpg" width="550" height="312" alt="Woman holding a pad of paper, with an arrow point up, and the words &amp;quot;21st Century Skills&amp;quot; above the arrow. " style="float: left;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1501083663</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1095">
        <pagenum>7</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Research shows employers seek employees with 21st century skills</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;In addition, 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; century workers need to be able to apply their writing and math skills to work-based problems and be able to communicate with colleagues and clients to develop customized solutions (Carnevale, 2008). These points are echoed in numerous studies. Notice how the skills cited in the surveys below echo the workforce preparation activities outlined in WIOA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A survey of 400 U.S. employers (across multiple industries) indicates that the skills most important to them are professionalism/work ethic, oral and written communications, teamwork/collaboration, and critical thinking/problem solving&lt;span style="background-color: #ffffff;"&gt; (“&lt;i&gt;Are they really ready&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;…,” 2006).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manufacturers have reported that while they observe deficient math and science skills in their workforce, the skills they find most lacking are problem-solving and the ability to analyze and communicate information rather than just absorb or memorize it (Manufacturing Institute, 2011).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In another survey of employers, the following were ranked as very important by the majority of respondents when asked about the skills they seek in college graduates:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;effective written and oral communication;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;working effectively in teams; ethical judgement and decision-making;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;critical thinking/analytical reasoning; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;applying knowledge to real-world settings (Hart Research Associates, 2015).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="550" height="300" alt="Picture of a man climbing white steps, with the words &amp;quot;problem&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;solutins&amp;quot;, and &amp;quot;success&amp;quot;. " src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/ProbSolutionSuccess.jpg" style="float: left;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1501083681</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1096">
        <pagenum>8</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Other workforce-related activities:  the scope of workforce preparation activities is broader than typical workforce training or job readiness </title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;The scope of workforce preparation activities as it is delineated in WIOA is broader and more expansive than other, more narrowly defined, workforce-related activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the terms&lt;span style="background-color: #ffffff;"&gt; &lt;i&gt;workforce training&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;occupational skills training&lt;/i&gt; refer to instruction aimed at teaching the competencies and knowledge needed to attain employment and career advancement in a specific occupation or occupational cluster. This type of training requires input from business and industry to define the skills and competencies required for a specific career and occupational pathway.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: #ffffff;"&gt;Another set of terms commonly used workforce-related activities are &lt;i&gt;job readiness&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;work readiness&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; These terms typically refer to a set of activities that teach and reinforce the skills and procedures involved in the seeking and securing a job, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;writing a resume;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;searching job postings;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;completing an application; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;interviewing for a job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, typical job or work readiness instruction might include topics such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;workplace etiquette and rules;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;standards of dress; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;punctuality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These behaviors are important and transferable across multiple work settings. But as we learned from employer surveys, employers are concerned about more than punctuality and etiquette; they are concerned about communication and problem-solving skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, the list of workforce preparation activities found in WIOA indicates a far more comprehensive set of interpersonal, intrapersonal, and cognitive skills that are deemed as essential for success in the 21st century across multiple domains – the workplace, personal life, civic and community life, and education (Shechtman et al., 2016). They include important life skills as well as those required for postsecondary education, and should be embedded into all levels of adult education and literacy services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;" face="Calibri" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: Verdana; font-size: small;" face="Verdana" size="2" color="#693300"&gt;Continue to Workforce Preparation Activities: Skills.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1502802244</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1097">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>How workforce preparation activities are connected to other allowable activities</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Workforce preparation activities are activities, programs, or services designed to help individuals gain the skills crucial for the world of work. The WIOA definition, containing the skills and competencies that define workforce preparation, can be found on the previous page. Adult education and literacy instruction has traditionally supported the development of these skills under definitions of employability skills, which will be described in more detail in this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workforce preparation is essential and there are many ways adult education programs can integrate this aspect into programming as part of an overall adult education approach, including career pathways. Illustrative examples are listed on the next page. Before full implementation, and in consideration of the specific role and the integration of workforce preparation, it is important to understand the differences between the type(s) of approaches being considered, as well as the particular components that are distinct but integrated as part of the overall program approach. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As programs consider how to integrate workforce preparation activities into programming, they should consider that not all examples described are definitively suitable, or needed, for every adult education participant. Nor may they be fully applicable to all programs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also important to keep in mind that there are flexibilities in implementing an approach that works best for your regional/local context based on factors such as but not limited to: learner’s literacy needs, type of industry partnerships and the corresponding skills crucial for success in the workplace, and the existing career pathways or programmatic structure as you consider the most appropriate approach in addressing the workforce preparation needs of individuals with barriers to employment.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1502799938</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1098">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Examples of how workforce preparation activities can be integrated into adult education</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Illustrative examples for integrating workforce preparation into adult education, including career pathways, programming can include:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Example #1: Integrating Workforce Preparation Activities into ABE/ASE or ESL instruction.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Adult education programs can integrate workforce preparation activities into ABE/ASE or ESL instruction. This course describes many examples of how instructors can integrate these transferrable workforce preparation activities into all levels of instruction. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Example #2: Contextualizing Workforce Preparation Activities to a Particular Occupation or Sector&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scenario: 1) Adult education programs can contextualize adult education and workforce preparation activities to a specific occupation or sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scenario: 2) These programs could consider developing a transfer course, or on-ramps to next steps along a career pathway such as a bridge course to a workforce training program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Example #3: IET&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Workforce preparation activities are one of three WIOA required program components of IET programs.   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IET is a service approach, which means that it refers to how services are organized and packaged for learners. Programs that provide adult and literacy activities concurrently and contextually with workforce preparation activities &lt;b&gt;and&lt;/b&gt; workforce training for a specific sector are considered IET programs (see graphic below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 1.5em;"&gt; &lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/pg13_SmartArt_for_IET.jpg" width="500" height="100" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span size="3" style="font-size: small;"&gt;Example #4: IELCE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span size="3" style="font-size: small;"&gt;IELCE must be offered in combination with IET. In addition to the requirements of IET (including workforce preparation activities), programs offering IELCE must offer IET activities alongside literacy, English language acquisition, and civics education. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span size="3" style="font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/pg13_SmartArt_IELCE.jpg" width="500" height="75" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Clearly, workforce preparation activities are a critical and required component, serving as a building block for programs interested in offering IET or IELCE programs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1502800084</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1099">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Adult education and literacy activites: WIOA workforce preparation activities</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;WIOA describes workforce preparation activities as activities, programs, and services to help an individual acquire a combination of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basic academic skills;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;critical thinking skills;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;digital literacy skills; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;self-management skills; as well as&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;competencies in
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;utilizing resources;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using information;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;working with others;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;understanding systems; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;obtaining skills necessary for successful transition into and completion of postsecondary education or training, or employment (WIOA. 2014. Sec 203).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These skills will be examined in more detail later in this session.  &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>1</hidden>
        <timemodified>1501035494</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>