<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="163" moduleid="6313" modulename="book" contextid="24993">
  <book id="163">
    <name>Additional Resources</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;INSTER DESCRIPTION HERE&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1495727316</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1495727316</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1158">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Workforce Preparation Activities Meant to be Integrated into all Adult Education Services</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Workforce preparation activities are not intended as a set of separate, stand-alone services. Nor are they reserved only for programming designed explicitly to prepare students for a specific occupation, such as Integrated Education and Training, Career Pathways, or Integrated English Literacy and Civics Education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, workforce preparation activities are meant to be integrated into &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; levels of adult education services, regardless of whether the programming is designed to prepare students for a specific occupation or career pathway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explore LINCS and other federal resources for states and programs interested in developing career pathways to familiarize yourself with them. Bookmark those you feel are relevant to your classroom instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Explore&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Federal Government has developed many, high-quality and in-depth resources for states and programs interested in developing career pathways, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul type="disc"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The U.S. Department of Labor &lt;a href="https://careerpathways.workforcegps.org/announcements/2016/10/20/09/37/Career_Pathways_Toolkit_An_Enhanced_Guide_and_Workbook"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Career Pathways Toolkit: An Enhanced Guide and Workbook for System Development&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;. &lt;/i&gt;Component 3.3 has several resources and tools around developing competency models that can be foundational to the development and design of a career pathway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OCTAE’s suite of self-paced &lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/learning-portal#pathways"&gt;Career Pathways online courses&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;i&gt;Building Strategic Partnerships&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Developing Effective Bridge Programs&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Designing Contextualized Instruction&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Integrating Career Counseling and Planning into Adult Education&lt;/i&gt;; and &lt;i&gt;Engaging Employers in Adult Career Pathways&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://careerpathways.workforcegps.org/announcements/2016/10/20/09/37/Career_Pathways_Toolkit_An_Enhanced_Guide_and_Workbook"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: Verdana; font-size: small;" color="#693300" face="Verdana" size="2"&gt;Continue to the &lt;b&gt;Comprehension Check.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt; &lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Calibri;" face="Calibri"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1502809151</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>