<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="160" moduleid="6309" modulename="book" contextid="24989">
  <book id="160">
    <name>NC-NET Employability Skills Resource Toolkit</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;INSERT DESCRIPTION HERE&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1495726478</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1511984399</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1149">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>NC-NET employability skills resource toolkit addresses employability competencies</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.nc-net.info/employability.php" target="_blank"&gt;North Carolina Network for Excellence (NC-NET) Employability Skills Resource Toolkit&lt;/a&gt; was developed by the Center for Occupational Research and Development (CORD) for North Carolina Community College System (NCCS) under the guidance and support of the NC Network for Excellence in Teaching (NC-NET). NCCS engaged more than 200 Career and Technical Education (CTE) faculty across the state in a Curriculum Improvement Project. The project committee was charged with reviewing and revising course curriculum and standards to respond to skill gaps identified by employers in North Carolina and around the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Resource Toolkit addresses the employability competencies identified by the project committee to be integrated across the curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This topic introduces the Resource Toolkit and describes the key features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="400" height="505" style="display: block; border: 1px solid black; margin-left: NaNpx; margin-right: NaNpx;" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/NC-NET%20Screenshot%20first%20page_PDF_7-11.JPG" alt="Screenshot of the first page of the NC-NET Employability Skills Resource Toolkit " /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1502807502</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1150">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Eight employability competencies align with workforce preparation activities</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;The eight employability competencies identified by the Curriculum Improvement Project committee align with the workforce preparation activities defined under WIOA. The NC-NET Employability Skills Resource Toolkit dedicates a module for each competency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Resource Toolkit was not developed specifically by and for the adult basic education field, adult educators, especially at the Secondary Education and Bridge or Transition level, will find the activities applicable. Teachers can adapt the activities to suit any level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="345" height="405" style="display: block;" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Employability%20Competencies%20Clipboard_Storyboard_7-11.png" alt="Clipboard with a list of the eight employability competencies: 1) Interpersonal Skills and Teamwork; 2) Communications; 3) Integrity and Professionalism; 4) Problem Solving and Decision Making; 5) Initiative and Dependability; 6) Information Processing; 7) Adaptability and Lifelong Learning; 8) Entrepreneurship" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1501086761</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1151">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Key features of the resource toolkit</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Some key features of the NC-NET Employability Competencies Resource Toolkit are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eight modules, each devoted to one of the eight employability competencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comprehensive instructional materials including:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;activity instructions;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;handouts;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;student reflection questions;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assessment rubrics; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a slide presentation, annotated with teacher talking points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neither the eight competencies nor the instructional activities associated with them are explicitly aligned with any set of content standards.&lt;a id="_anchor_1" href="#_msocom_1" language="JavaScript" name="_msoanchor_1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activities are very interactive and hands-on. Many involve role plays, case scenarios and collaborative problem-solving tasks that apply primarily to workplace or school/college contexts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p class="MoreInfoBox"&gt;On December 3rd, 2014, the LINCS Community hosted a webinar entitled "Implementing the&lt;span class="nolink"&gt; Employability Skills Framework in the Adult Basic Education Classroom."&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MoreInfoBox"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IkqqllDqQxM&amp;amp;list=PLImUeO1ttx1YXcxwSjA6FndV4qQtia0Cr&amp;amp;index=4"&gt;webinar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MoreInfoBox"&gt;In Part IV of this webinar, Dr. Robert Witchger and Frank Scuiletti from the North Carolina Community College System discuss strategies and resources for teaching employability skills. A resource highlighted during this section is North Carolina's Employability Skills Toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1500383536</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1152">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Explore the NC-NET employability skills resource toolkit</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Take a few moments to explore the NC-NET Employability Skills Resource Toolkit with these questions in mind. Record your notes in this writeable, printable PDF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;" face="Calibri" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: Verdana; font-size: small;" face="Verdana" size="2" color="#693300"&gt;After you have completed this learning activity, click NC-NET Employability Skills Resource Toolkit Reflection Questions, to complete the reflection questionnaire. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1500383568</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>