<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="152" moduleid="6294" modulename="book" contextid="24973">
  <book id="152">
    <name>Course Introduction</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;Course description and learning objectives.&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1495209632</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1511984133</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1085">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Course overview and goals</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;The passage of the WIOA in 2014 has increased the need for&lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*6319@$&amp;amp;mode=entry&amp;amp;hook=310"&gt; adult education and literacy&lt;/a&gt; providers to deliver instruction that increases learners’ academic skills and prepares them for successful transitions to postsecondary education, training, and employment or advancement in the workplace. To this end, WIOA outlines a set of allowable workforce preparation activities to prepare learners for these educational and employment outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary goal of this course is to introduce and unpack the workforce preparation activities outlined in WIOA and present examples of the evidence base that forms the foundation of this more comprehensive notion of workforce preparation skills and competencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Session 2 provides rich resources educators can use to incorporate workforce preparation activities into all types of services and programming and into all levels of curriculum and instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: Verdana; font-size: small;" color="#693300" face="Verdana" size="2"&gt;Continue to Importance of Workforce Preparation Activities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt; &lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Calibri;" face="Calibri"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1502801973</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1086">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Join the LINCS community and participate in course discussions</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="nolink"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;As with all LINCS courses, this course provides opportunities to connect with other adult educators. If you haven’t already done so, take a moment to explore the&lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov" target="_parent"&gt; LINCS Community&lt;/a&gt;. Throughout this course, there are embedded discussions hosted in the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/group/career-pathways" target="_parent"&gt;LINCS Career Pathways &lt;/a&gt;group. &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;Please log in to the community and share your thoughts, ideas, and questions with other adult education practitioners. This is a great opportunity to share and learn from others.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="550" height="424" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="Screenshot LINCS Community Website" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/LINCS%20Community%20Screenshot_7-11.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1501169409</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1087">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Introduction &amp; learning objectives</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the&lt;span style="background-color: #ffffff;"&gt; &lt;i&gt;&lt;span class="nolink"&gt;Introduction to Workforce Preparation and Employability Skills&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/i&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;ourse. This course is designed for adult educators, administrators, teachers, and advisors who seek an introduction to the general concept of workforce preparation and the specific skills outlined in the U.S. Department of Education’s&lt;span class="nolink"&gt; Employability Skills Framework.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After completing this course, you will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;understand what constitutes the workforce preparation activities referenced in the &lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*6319@$&amp;amp;mode=entry&amp;amp;hook=321" target="_blank"&gt;Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (WIOA)&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;explain how to integrate workforce preparation activities into &lt;a href="$@GLOSSARYVIEWBYID*6319@$&amp;amp;mode=entry&amp;amp;hook=309" target="_blank"&gt;adult education&lt;/a&gt; programming and instruction; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;locate resources you can use to develop and incorporate workforce preparation activities into curriculum and instruction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please allow approximately 90 minutes to complete this course (45 minutes for session 1 and 45 minutes for session 2). However, you are free to leave the session at any time. When you exit the courseware, a bookmark is automatically placed at your last location to allow you to pick up where you left off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cours&lt;span style="background-color: #ffffff;"&gt;e is the first in a two-part series exploring workforce preparation skills. The second course, &lt;i&gt;Workforce Preparation Activities in the Classroom: Contextualizing Employability Skills for Deeper Learning&lt;/i&gt;, will focus on the implementation of workforce preparation activities in the adult education classroom.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="boxed"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: Verdana; font-size: small;" color="#693300" face="Verdana" size="2"&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; to continue.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt; &lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Calibri;" face="Calibri"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1511376882</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>