<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="157" moduleid="6304" modulename="book" contextid="24984">
  <book id="157">
    <name>Employability Skills Framework</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;dryrdyh&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1495484625</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1511984348</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1138">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Introducing the employability skills framework</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Education’s Office of Career, Technical, and Adult Education (OCTAE) &lt;a href="http://cte.ed.gov/employabilityskills/"&gt;Employability Skills Framework&lt;/a&gt; offers a vision that is broader and deeper than traditional job readiness activities and aligns substantially with the workforce preparation skills and competencies that WIOA seeks to address through workforce preparation activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development of the Employability Skills Framework was informed by research and input from stakeholders in career and technical education, adult education, workforce development, and business organizations. The intention was to develop a unifying framework that cuts across all of these sectors, rather than develop a set of duplicative standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Employability Skills Framework resources can be used to inform classroom instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width="550" height="429" style="display: block; margin-left: NaNpx; margin-right: NaNpx;" alt="Screenshot Employability Skills Framework Website" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Employability%20Skills%20Framework%20Screenshot_7-11.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: Verdana; font-size: small;" color="#693300" face="Verdana" size="2"&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; to continue.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt; &lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Calibri;" face="Calibri"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1502807110</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1139">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Employability skills framework - source matrix</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;The Employability Skills Framework is an interactive tool to help educators—career and technical, K-12, workplace, and adult education—incorporate employability skills into instruction. The framework is based on a review of over 20 existing standards, assessments, and skill descriptors related to employability. It is the result of a &lt;a href="http://cte.ed.gov/employabilityskills/index.php/framework/source_matrix"&gt;cross-walking process &lt;/a&gt;to identify overlapping and mutually reinforcing skills across the various frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Employability Skills Framework&lt;a href="http://cte.ed.gov/employabilityskills/app/webroot/files/Employability_Skills_Framework.pdf"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; identifies nine general skills necessary for success in the labor market at all employment levels and all sectors. These nine skills are sorted into three broad categories and overlap substantially with the workforce preparation activities delineated in WIOA:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applied Knowledge;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective Relationships; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workplace Skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1501086046</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1140">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Employability skills framework - skill checklist</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;As discussed previously, the emphasis is on embedding employability skills into ongoing instruction rather than developing separate lessons or workshops focused on workforce preparation or employability skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expectation is not that a single lesson or even a series of lessons or units will address all of the employability skills. The goal is for programs and teachers to be able to identify gaps and opportunities within their ongoing curriculum where they can embed, underscore, and highlight the employability skills into their instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that end, the Employability Skills website provides a &lt;a href="http://cte.ed.gov/employabilityskills/index.php/developingskills/create_checklist"&gt;Lesson Planning Checklist&lt;/a&gt; that can be used by teachers, advisors, administrators, and even employers to identify priority workforce preparation/employability skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The checklist fleshes out each of the skills in greater detail, signaling how they might be incorporated into activities, observed, and assessed. In itself, this is a valuable feature of the checklist. Further: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teachers can use the checklist to plan lessons and track lessons where employability skills are explicitly taught, practiced, and reinforced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advisors can use the checklist to teach students about the skills they’ll need to achieve their educational and career goals and help them reflect on their progress in attaining these skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administrators can use the checklist to establish program-wide priorities, lead curriculum development, and assess the extent to which the curriculum explicitly addresses workforce preparation and employability skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employer partners can use the checklist to identify the employability skills they most seek in candidates to help programs design career pathways, workplace education, and other industry or sector-focused education programs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conjunction with the Lesson Planning Checklist, there are &lt;a href="http://cte.ed.gov/employabilityskills/index.php/developingskills/checklist"&gt;example scenarios&lt;/a&gt; of how the different audiences can use the Checklist as a tool for developing and assessing employability skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class="Label"&gt;&lt;img width="450" height="361" style="display: block; margin-left: NaNpx; margin-right: NaNpx;" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/workshop%20thumbnails.JPG" alt="Thumbnails of the four workshop resources: powerpoint slides, facilitator's guide, workbook and sample training agenda" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Label"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #693300; font-family: Verdana; font-size: small;" color="#693300" face="Verdana" size="2"&gt;Continue on to the Transitions Integration Framework.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br clear="all" /&gt; &lt;span style="font-family: Times New Roman; font-size: medium;" face="Times New Roman" size="3"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Calibri;" face="Calibri"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1502807152</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>